

JOHNNY DODSON

GRAPHIC DESIGNER

Contact

Address Sparta, TN 38583

Email jddodson1@alumni. fullsail.edu

Phone 931-254-0738

Skills

- PC and Mac platforms
- Illustration
- Visual design
- Digital imagery
- Digital design
- Project Management Abilities
- Photography Composition
- Image Manipulation
- Digital Graphics
- Adobe Creative Suite
- Graphic design
- Logo design
- Photoshop
- Illustrator
- InDesign
- Xd
- Keynote
- Premiere Pro
- Website graphics
- Photography composition
- Image manipulation
- Customer service
- Branding strategies
- Production layouts

Education

Full Sail University

Winter Park, Florida • 04/2021 Bachelor of Science: Graphic Design

TN College of Applied Technology

McMinnville, TN • 04/1996

Certificate: Machinist

Portfolio

www.jdodsondesigns.com

Professional Summary

Deadline-driven Graphic Designer focused on overseeing projects from concept through final delivery. Successfully creates brand messages, strategies and key graphic productions. Creative Graphic Designer with talent for developing unique custom artwork.

Innovative approach to idea and concept development.

Offering over two year of expertise overseeing individual projects and brand development.

Experience

Self-employed - Freelance Graphic Designer Sparta, TN • 04/2019 - Current

- Designed website layouts, templates and unique branded looks.
- Worked with clients to gather and define requirements, establish scopes and managing project milestones
- Completed in-depth product design tests with help of different software, models and design systems
- Developed print materials such as brochures, banners and signs
- Uses the Adobe Creative Suite to create images and layouts

Self-employed - E-commerce Manager

Sparta, TN • 07/2017 - 6/2018

- Optimized e-commerce fulfillment strategy to minimize costs while maximizing profits and customer satisfaction
- Responded to customer issues and resolved complaints

Self-employed - Woodworking Business

Sparta, TN • 06/2011 - 8/2017

• Worked with a variety of wood to transform them into furniture, bird houses/feeders, tables, and much more

Self-employed - Woodworking Business

Sparta, TN • 01/2008 - 6/2015

- Worked with all types of weather and ground conditions
- Sold designs
- Installed vinyl signs, decals, and lettering

DCS - Children's Services Officer

Cookeville, TN • 01/2004 - 11/2007

- Maintained accurate records and full compliance with government regulations and agency guidelines
- Hearing Officer
- Fire & Chemical Officer

Office Mart - Delivery/Sales

Cookeville, TN • 05/2000 - 01/2004

- Helped customers locate products and checked store system for merchandise at other sites
- Delivery of office furniture and assembly
- Office supply sales

Affiliations

- AIGA Member
- Lifetime member of The National Society of Collegiate Scholars

Awards

• Four course director's awards in Graphic Design